fonality.com 2008-12-18

# Fonality Privacy Policy | Fonality

**General**  
Fonality takes your privacy and the confidentiality of your business data very seriously. We understand that your phone system is critical to your business, and that you need to trust that system and the company that provides it fully.

This policy outlines the types of information Fonality may collect, and our commitment to keeping that information safe, secure and private. 

**Collection and Use of Customer Information**  
Fonality provides a service where our customers upload and store their system configuration information and call statistics data on Fonality servers and equipment. Customers using have the ability to disable the collection of call statistics data, which will cause all call data to be stored locally on the customer’s server. Disabling this data collection will disable any available graphical reporting capabilities.

In addition, Fonality software gives customers, at their discretion, the ability to record and save voicemails, phones calls and chats. All communications content is stored locally on the customer’s server(s), and unless provided for under a separate service contract, Fonality does not store any voicemail, call recordings, chats or other communications. 

Fonality does not review, edit, disseminate, or use individual customer information, data or communications in any way, except to investigate a technical support request initiated by a customer, to investigate a suspected Terms of Use violation or as may be required by law. We may use aggregated, non-identifiable usage statistics to assess system performance and scale.

**No Monitoring of Customer Communications**  
All phone calls are routed locally on the customer’s individual system, and externally via the customer’s selected communications service providers. Fonality does not provide voice services, and customer phone calls or other voice communications do not access or otherwise pass through the Fonality network. Fonality does not monitor the content of any phone calls.

**Maintenance of Optional Secure Connection to Fonality**  
In order to monitor the performance of your system, provide you with technical support and provide product enhancements and upgrades, Fonality by default maintains a secure electronic connection to your server(s). Fonality implements numerous security techniques to ensure the safety of customer data and system access and to minimize the risk of network intrusion. 

Customers can, at their discretion, elect to disconnect this connection. Disconnecting the connection will prevent the administration of your server(s), and will disable other important features, including graphical reporting.

In addition, we will not be able to provide technical support or software updates until the connection is re-established.

Fonality provides additional information on maximizing the security of a PBXtra installation in our KnowledgeBase at <http://help.pbxtra.com/index.php/Tips_for_Security_and_Performance>

**Billing Information**  
When Fonality bills for services rendered, a third-party processing company is used to charge customer credit cards and collect payment. This third-party is used only to process credit card charges, and does not store or distribute customer credit card or billing information.

**Fonality Web Properties**  
Fonality may collect information from visitors to the [http://www.Fonality.com](http://www.fonality.com/ "http://www.Fonality.com"), [http://pbxtra.fonality.com](http://pbxtra.fonality.com/ "http://pbxtra.fonality.com"), [http://trixbox.fonality.com](http://trixbox.fonality.com/ "http://trixbox.fonality.com") and [http://www.trixbox.org](http://www.trixbox.org/ "http://www.trixbox.org") web sites, or any other web sites operated by Fonality. We may collect the Internet addresses of Fonality site visitors. We use the information that we log from the Fonality website to both improve our services, and help troubleshoot possible Fonality website problems. We may also analyze non-identifying statistics that we collect from website visitor usage, and provide this data to qualified third parties.

Additionally, Fonality web properties may contain content from third-party content providers, but these content providers neither receive nor distribute Fonality user or customer information, nor do they receive user or customer information from Fonality.

**Electronic and Physical Mailing Addresses**  
Fonality requires a valid, working e-mail address upon account setup in order to send account information details, including account username and password. If you wish to receive no further communications from Fonality after the installation process is complete, you may send a request at [http://support.fonality.com](http://support.fonality.com/ "http://support.fonality.com"). Removal from this list will significantly limit our ability to provide you with technical support.

In addition, Fonality may periodically communicate with you regarding new products, product updates, and important Fonality news and information. 

You have the option to exclude yourself from these communications. If you would like to cease receiving communications from Fonality, please send a request [http://support.fonality.com](http://support.fonality.com/ "http://support.fonality.com") with the subject line “UNSUBSCRIBE”. 

We will not sell or distribute your e-mail or physical address to any third party, other than a) a qualified provider of services to Fonality who also subscribes to the terms of this Privacy Policy or b) with your express permission, to a qualified Fonality partner upon your request.

**Cookies**  
Our sites use cookies to enhance the user's experience by allowing us to recognize a user's return visit to our own service. Browsers are usually set to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you may alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to have their browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of our site will not function as effectively, and you may be unable to log into our web based administration tools, preventing the administration of your system.

Further, we may use a third party to provide statistical analysis regarding our web users and may set cookies in order to gather the information needed to perform their statistical analysis. The information collected by the third party cookies does not contain any personal information and cannot be linked back to any individual user.

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Links**  
Our web sites may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by Fonality web properties site or the Fonality application.

**Surveys**  
From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information and demographic information. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site or of the Fonality application.

**Security**  
Fonality implements numerous security techniques to ensure the safety of customer data and system access. If you are accessing our site with 4.0 versions or higher of Microsoft Internet Explorer or Netscape Navigator browsers, your information is encrypted and authenticated, using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. The SSL systems provide data security for you and your users, and the authentication ensures that your valuable content is available only to registered users, and is not accessible to unwanted parties. Each registered user in your organization is provided with a unique username and password. Each time a user logs onto your Fonality application, they can only be authenticated and allowed access using the correct username and password that has been assigned. A session is issued for the purpose of capturing encrypted authentication data for the length of the session. Neither the username nor the password is included in the session. Security protocols put into operation by Fonality are determined by encrypted session Ids and dynamic data. 

**Children's Privacy Policy**  
Fonality does not sell products or services for purchase by children. Fonality does not knowingly solicit or collect customer identifiable information from children or teenagers under the age of eighteen. In addition, Fonality will not knowingly link to any third party web site that solicits or collects customer identifiable information from minors. If you believe that a minor has disclosed personally identifiable information to Fonality, please contact Fonality at [http://support.fonality.com](http://support.fonality.com/ "http://support.fonality.com") so that the information can be removed.

**Your Responsibilities**  
We promise to be extremely careful with any information you entrust us with, and we would ask that you do the same. This includes ensuring the physical and electronic security of your network, and maintaining the privacy and confidentiality of your own data, usernames and passwords. 

**Additional Information**  
If you have any questions about this Statement or the practices of our website, you can send a request at [http://support.fonality.com](http://support.fonality.com/ "http://support.fonality.com").
